Guide to the Guido Kisch papers, [ca. 1934-1972].
Kisch, Guido papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Guido Kisch papers, [ca. 1934-1972].
6314
Kisch, Guido,
2.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, manuscripts, publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, manuscripts, professional papers and writings, reviews, publishing correspondence, syllabi, essays, dissertations, notes, meeting agendas, and other papers.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Born Prague, the son of Alexander Kisch, the Chief Rabbi of that city; Author; humanist scholar; Professor of law, Jewish history and bibliography, and Jewry law at the University of Leipzig, the University of Halle, and the Jewish Institute of Religion (New York), later Hebrew-Union College; also Honorary Professor at the University of Basel; founder and editor of Historia Judaica.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, manuscripts, professional papers and writings, reviews, publishing correspondence, syllabi, essays, dissertations, notes, meeting agendas, and other papers of Guido Kisch, relating to German legal history, humanist scholarship, Jewry law, publishing, and to his professional career as author and professor.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kisch, Guido, 1889-1985.
Subjects:
Judaism -- History.; Jewish law -- Study and teaching; Law -- Study and teaching -- Germany.; Jews -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Germany.; Jews -- History -- Germany.; Jewish learning and scholarship.; Jewish law -- Study and teaching; Jewish learning and scholarship; Jews; Jews -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Judaism; Law -- Study and teaching; Jewish authors.
Places:
Germany
Form and Genre Terms:
History
RELATED MATERIALS
See also: Guido Kisch Collection at the Leo Baeck Institute, Center for Jewish History, New York: http://digifindingaids.cjh.org/?pID=229838
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- "Zum Stand der Forschung über die Geschichte der Juden in Deutschland" (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence from Griggs Gartebuch and photos of 1615 text, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence and "Recherches Augustiniennes" by Bernhard Blumenkranz, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence to a Colleague and "Archiv für Kulturgeschichte", 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence to a Colleague and "David Gans: Disciple du Maharal de Prague et assistant de Tycho Brahe et de Jean Kepler", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "The Mystery of the Jews in Mickiewicz's Towianist Lectures on Slav Literature" by Abraham G. Duker and related Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Die jüdische Glaubensgemeinschaft" and related Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Papers About "Narben bleiben zurück", 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Kirche and Synagogue: Handbuch zur Geschichte von Christen und Juden" and Related Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Die Familie der Luise Wolfs" and related Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Untitled Journal with Contents related to Jewish Research (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "Harz-Zeitschrift für den Harz-Verein für Geschichte und Altertumskunde Herausgegeben von K.W. Sanders" and related Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "The Origin of the Hallel" and Thank-you from Kisch, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "The Jews of Austria" edited by Josef Fraenkel and related Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- ""Yivo Annual of Jewish Social Science Vol. 12," "Offprint from Year Book 7 of the Leo Baeck Institute of Jews from Germany," and related Corresppondence, 1958-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "Rabbinic Methods of Interpretation and Hellenistic Rhetoric" by David Daube and related Corresponse, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Assorted Correspondence Concerning Recent Work, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- "Die Familie der Luise Wolfs" and related Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- "La Bible versifiee de Jehan Malkaraume et lÁurora" by P. E. Beichner and related Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "Leo Baeck Institute New York Bibliothek Und Archiv: Katalog Band I" and related Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Papers and Correspondence Related to "Urkunden aus Wiener Grundbüchern zur Geschichte der Wiener Juden im Mittelalter", 1931 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Correspondence Related to Texts, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Academic Information from the Jewish Institute of Religion, May 1942 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, October 20, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, Some Discussing Texts, September-December 1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Correspondence Pertaining to Study, April 16, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Personal Correspondence, October 29, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- "Interest Taken by Jews from Gentiles," by S. Stein in the "Journal of Semitic Studies", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Scholarly Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Correspondence Surrounding the "Formularium" and its Interpretation, February-March 1957 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Correspondence Concerning Texts and Book Orders, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- "The Seminary's First Alumnus: Chief Rabbi Joseph Herman Herts: Memorial Address Delivered at the Jewish Theological Seminary" by Dr. Elias L. Solomon, February 13, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Correspondence Concerning Texts, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Correspondence on the Exchange of Articles, 1953-1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- "Martin Bucer and His Influence on the Jewish Situation" by Carl Cohen and related Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- "Der Fall Opet:" Eine Studie zum Leben der deutschen Vorkriegsuniversität" by Ernst J. Cohn and related Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- "Beiträge zur Spätmittelalterlichen deutschen Prosa aus Handschriften und Frühdrucken" by Gerhard Ers and related Correspondence, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Jewish Institute of Religion Academic Papers, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- "Hermann Cohen and Heinrich Graety," by Erwin I. J. Rosenthal and related Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- "Rivkind" Labeled Hebrew Article and Related Papers (Box 1, Folder 41)
- "Der Moderne Antisemitismus und seine Bedeutung für die Judenfrage" by Alexander Bein and realted Correspondence, 1958-1970 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Jewish Institute of Religion Academic Papers, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Correspondence about Rabbinic History, November 1943 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- History Class, Student Papers and Concern, Spring 1945 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Correspondence about Morris Shapiro's Thesis, May-June 1947 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Correspondence about Theses of Paul Siegel and Azriel Gushman, December 1947 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Correspondence on Incomplete Class Performance by David Greenberg and Friedman, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Medieval Academy of America, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- "The Metropolitan Council B'Nai Honors Barney Balaban", 1954 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Times Articles on Dr. London, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Correspondence Between Kisch and Students, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Correspondence Between Kisch and Maurice Bloom, November-December 1940 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Correspondence Between Isadore Budick and Kisch, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Correspondence Between Leo Shubow and Kisch, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Correspondence Between Meyer Greenberg and Kisch, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Correspondence Between Judah Caln and Kisch, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Correspondence Between Harry Gutstein and Kisch, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Correspondence Between Joseph Messing and Kisch, February 1948 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Correspondence Centering Around Harold Silver, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Correspondence about Rabbinic History, November 1943 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- "Correspondence Concerning the Journal Of Jewish Bibliography", 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- "The Medieval German Jewry-Law" by Kisch, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- "'Judenrecht' als wissenschaftliche Disziplin" Von Ismar Elbogen (Box 1, Folder 64)
- "Magdeburg Jury Court Decisions as Sources of Jewry-Law" by Guido Kisch, April 1943 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- "A Talmudic Legend as the Source for the Josephus Passage in the 'Sachsenspiegel'" by Kisch, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Correspondence in German, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- "Neue Judaica: Angezeigt" von Dr. E. G. Lowenthal (Box 1, Folder 68)
- "Amerika-Israel-Deutschland: Neue Judaica - im weiteseten Sinn" von Dr. E. G. Lowenthal (Box 1, Folder 69)
- American Jewish Archives Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Correspondence in German, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Correspondence Concerning Studies, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Correspondence Between Professors, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Correspondence Between Doctor Sterling and Kisch, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Correspondence Between Herman Hailperin and Kisch, January 1956 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- American-Czechslovak Gift Parcel Co. Flyer and Related Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Correspondence Between Leon Watters and Kisch, December 1955 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- American Men of Science Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Memorial Meeting for Mark Wischnitzer, December 1955 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Correspondence Between Kölliker and Kisch, November 1955 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Letter from Hilde Kisch to Dr. Hailperin about "Festschrift" Award, November 9, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Correspondence Between Leo Jung and Kisch about the Jewish Academy of Arts, October 1955 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- Correspondence Concerning José Millás, March-September 1955 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Papers and Correspondence on Publications, February 1955 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Correspondence with Selma Stein-Taeubler, September-December 1954 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- Assorted Correspondence Concerning Bibliography, October 1954-March 1956 (Box 1, Folder 86)
- "Zur Einflussphäre der 'Vorlesungen' Hugos von St. Viktor" von Heinrich Weisweiler and Related Correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 87)
- "Zur Kompositionstechnik des Pseudo-Philonischen Liber Antiquitatum Biblicarum," by Otto Eissfeldt, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 88)
- Correspondence About Publications, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 89)
- Book Order and Related Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 90)
- Correspondence Between John B. Kaiser and Kisch, December 1969 (Box 1, Folder 91)
- Correspondence Between Max Weinreich and Kisch, November-December 1957 (Box 1, Folder 92)
- "Reformatio: Evanglische Zeitschrift für Kultur und Politik" and related Papers, February 1975 (Box 1, Folder 93)
- Veröffentlichungen der Historischen Kommission zu Berlin and related Papers, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 94)
- "Revue des études juives: Historia judaica" and related papers, April-September 1969 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- "Theologische Zeitschrift" and "Una paraphrase du cantique d'Anne", 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- "Judenexamina an der Universität Giessen vor 1800" and related Papers, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 97)
- "Correspondence Related to Magazine Subscription, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 98)
- Correspondence About Exchanges of Scholarship, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 99)
- "Bucher Section of "Allgemeine" (February 1969); "Keyath Sepher" Vol. 46 No. 2-3 (1971); "Judaica" 27 (1979), 1969-1979 (Box 1, Folder 100)
- (German)Reviews for Kisch's "Erasmus' Stellung zu Juden und Judentum", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 101)
- (French/English)Reviews for Kisch's "Erasmus' Stellung zu Juden und Judentum", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 102)
- Correspondence between Jürgen von Esenwein and Kisch, February-April 1974 (Box 1, Folder 103)
- Notes for Kisch on "Forschungen zur Rechts - und Sozialgeschichte der Juden in Deutschland während des Mittelalters", 1955; 1963 (Box 1, Folder 104)
- "Consilia: Eine Bibliographie der juristischen Konsiliensammlungen" (Flyer), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 105)
- "Zeitschrift der Savigny-Stiftung für Rechtsgeschichte" and related Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 106)
- Renaissance Quarterly's Review of Kisch's "Consilia: Eine Bibliographie der juristischen Konsiliensammlungen" and related Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 107)
- Comptes Rendu's Review of Kisch's "Consilia: Eine Bibliographie der juristischen Konsiliensammlungen", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 108)
- Assorted Reviews for Kische's Books (Box 1, Folder 109)
- Correspondence Between Daniel Lewin and Kisch, May-July 1942 (Box 1, Folder 110)
- Correspondence Between J. Rabin and Kisch, February 1929 (Box 1, Folder 111)
- Papers from Dinner in Honor of Louis Ginzberg, April 6. 1947 (Box 1, Folder 112)
- "Literargeschichtliches zum lateinischen Moses Maimonides" by W. Kluxen and related Correspondence, 1954-1963 (Box 1, Folder 113)
- "Geschichte des Krankenkassenwesens" von Dr. I. Fischer and related Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 114)
- "The Bibliography of Ancient Hebrew Medicine" with an Introductory Note by Harry Friedenwald" with related Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 115)
- "The People and the Book" by Joshua Bloch and related Correspondence, 19719440 (Box 1, Folder 116)
- Correspondence Between Wach and Kisch, Fall 1944 (Box 1, Folder 117)
- Correspondence with Society for Jewish History in the Czech Republic, April-May 1932 (Box 1, Folder 118)
- Sheet (Box 1, Folder 119)
- Correspondence Between Kisch and Desider Stern, April 1967 (Box 1, Folder 120)
- Correspondence Between Herman Hailperin and Kisch, as well as a Review of Hailperon's "Rashi and the Christian Scholars", 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 121)
- Announcement and Related Papers for Dr. Akiba Eisenburg's Book Exhibition, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 122)
- Correspondence Between Desider Stern and Kisch, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 123)
- Correspondence with Ekkehart Fabian, May 7, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 124)
- Correspondence with the Board of the Jewish Religious Community, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 125)
- Correspondence and Papers Concerning Kischs Book "Judentaufen: Eine historisch-biographisch-psychologisch-sozialogische Studie", 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 126)
- Letter Marking Book Receipt, May 13, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 127)
- Correspondence with Dr. Hahn, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 128)
- Correspondence about "The Cartwright Petition", April-May 1947 (Box 1, Folder 129)
- "Jüdische Briefe aus dem Jahre 1588" von Louis Lewin and related Correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 130)
- Papers related to "The Crusading Movement in its Bearing on the Christian Attitude towards Jewry" by H. Liebeschütz, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 131)
- "Bibliography of Jewish Bibliographies" by Schlomo Shunami and related Correspondence", 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 132)
- Correspondence from T. Simont o Kisch, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 133)
- Correspondence Between J. Kauffman and Kisch, June 1933 (Box 1, Folder 134)
- Kisch's Reviews and Related Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 135)
- Correspondence with Mrs. Oskar K. Rabinowicz, September 13, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 136)
- Letter from L. Rabinowitz to K isch Concerning New Book, December 6, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 137)
- Correspondence, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 138)
- Thank You to Grüner for Copy of "Die Juden in Deutschland während des Mittelalters", February 16, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 139)
- "Quellen zur Geschichte der Juden in Mähren" von Oskar Donoth and related Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 140)
- "Chronological Survey 1492-1789" from Jewish Institute of Religion, February 1958 (Box 1, Folder 141)
- "Studien zur Institution des Hofjudentums in Kurköln" von Heinrich Schnee and related Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 142)
- Papers related to Alexander Marx, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 143)
- "Archiv für Kommunalwissenschaften" Jahrgang 4/1965 with "Juden als Bürger deutscher Städte" by Adolf Leschnitzer, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 144)
- Correspondence Between Mitchell Kaplan and Kisch, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 145)
- Correspondence Between Gertrud Schubart-Fikentscher and Kisch, August-October 1963 (Box 1, Folder 146)
- Correspondence with Phil Salcia Landmann, December 31, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 147)
- Correspondence Between Mrs. Kisch and Mrs. Tambler, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 148)
- Correspondence Between Werner Schochow and Kisch, May 1967 (Box 1, Folder 149)
- Correspondence with Alexander Carlebach, March 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 150)
- Correspondence with Dr. Alfred Jospe, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 151)
- Correspondence Between "Speculum" and Kisch, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 152)
- Correspondence with A. Glaug, August 18, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 153)
- Correspondence About A. Rosenthal Gifting "History of the Jews in Baghdad" to Kisch, April 1950 (Box 1, Folder 154)
- Correspondence with Rudolf Deschen (Box 1, Folder 155)
- Correspondence Between Gerhard Veltwyck, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 156)
- Correspondence, March 18, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 157)
- Correspondence with Department of Western MSS. at Oxford about Scholarships, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 158)
- "Max Wiener's Reinterpretation of Liberal Judaism" by Hans Liebuschütz and related Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 159)
- Correspondence Recording Exchange of Literature, Fall 1932 (Box 1, Folder 160)
- "Professor Dr. Adolf Kurrein" von Dr. Viktor Kurrein and related Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 161)
- "Das Lebensbild eines Oberschlesischen Dichters" von Michael Fraenkel, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 162)
- Correspondence Between Solomon B. Freehof and Kisch, January 1962 (Box 1, Folder 163)
- Correspondence with Kurt Jähnig, Halle (Saale), 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 164)
- Correspondence Between J. Hohnholz and Kisch, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 165)
- Kisch's Review of Karl Heinrich Rengstorf's "Church and Synagogue: Handbook of Christian and Jewish History, V.II", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 166)
- Correspondence Between H. Wahl and Kisch About Archives (and related Articles), July 1965; 1975 (Box 1, Folder 167)
- Kisch's Review of Monika Richarz's "Judisches Leben in Deutschland" (Box 1, Folder 168)
- Correspondence with Dr. Freimann, August 3, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 169)
- Dinner in Honor of Leo Jung on the Occasion of His 70th Birthday, May-June 1962 (Box 1, Folder 170)
- Correspondence with Kisch (presumably with H. Tramer), February 11, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 171)
- Correspondence with Louis Ginzberg, April 29, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 172)
- Correspondence about French Texts, May 18, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 173)
- Papers and Correspondence about Georg and Helene Karo, 1960-1976 (Box 1, Folder 174)
- Correspondence with Florence Guggenheim and Related Review, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 175)
- Correspondence with Buchhandlung Gustav Fock, May-June 1934 (Box 1, Folder 176)
- Book Citations, September 1944 (Box 1, Folder 177)
- Kisch's Review of "Urkunden und Aktenstücke zur Geschichte der Juden in Reginsburg", April 12, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 178)
- "Gemeinschaft und Volksgemeinschaft: Zur juristischen Terminologie im Nationalsozialismus", April 1972 (Box 1, Folder 179)
- Pamphlets with Book Reviews and Bibliographies, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 180)
- Collection of Papers Related to books, including Reviews, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 181)
- "Die Juden und Luther" von Carl Cohen and related Papers, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 182)
- "Zeugen judischer Unschuld: Unbekanntes von Melanchthon und Osiander" von Carl Cohen, September 4, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 183)
- Papers and Correspondence about Solomon Katz's "The Jews in the Visigoothic and Frankish Kingdoms of Spain and Gaul", 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 184)
- Correspondence with Akademie-Verlag, December 6, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 185)
- Kisch's Review of Selma Stern's "Der Freussische Staat und die Juden", July 1975 (Box 1, Folder 186)
- Correspondence with Hans-Jürgen Krüger, January 7-9, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 187)
- Correspondence Between E. Battenberg and Kisch, April-June 1969 (Box 1, Folder 188)
- "Motive der evangelischen Bekenntnisbildung bei Luther und Melanchthon: by Wilhelm Maurer and related Papers, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 189)
- "Fremd-im eigenen Staat" by D. Herzog and related Correspondence, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 190)
- Correspondence Between John M. Oesterreicher and Kisch About Books, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 191)
- Correspondence with Scholars in Berlin, November 1932 (Box 1, Folder 192)
- Correspondence Between H. Gerig and Kisch, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 193)
- Correspondence Between Werner Ogris and Kisch, February-March 1972 (Box 1, Folder 194)
- Correspondence on Recent Book, October 13, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 195)
- Correspondence with Ludwig Kahn, May 20, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 196)
- Correspondence with Dr. Schmidt-Clausing, August 20, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 197)
- "The Ancestry and Descendence of Nanny Egers Engel" by John Henry Richter and related Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 198)
- 'Dr. Augusta Welder-Steinberg," Biography, November 18, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 199)
- Correspondence Between Weldler and Kisch, 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 200)
- Correspondence with Weldler, June 15-17, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 201)
- Correspondence with Kahn, March 24, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 202)
- Correspondence about Study on "Die Juden auf der Zurzacher Messe", October 13, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 203)
- Correspondence on Study "Der Friedhof auf der Judeninsel im Rhein bei Koblenz", January 15, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 204)
- Russian Correspondence, August 23, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 205)
- "Nationalism in the Middle Ages," by G.G. Coulton and related Papers by the Same Authors, 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 206)
- Folio Order Form, June 22, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 207)
- Correspondence Between Hedwig Herder and Kisch, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 208)
- Personal Correspondence Between Herman Hailperin and Kisch, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 209)
- Correspondence on Receiving Book Related to Jewish History, February 13, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 210)
- C. Erfurter Judeneid and related Papers (Box 1, Folder 211)
- Correspondence Between Helmut Heiber and Kisch, May 16, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 212)
- Related to History of Jews in France (Box 1, Folder 213)
- Correspondence Between H. Ridder and Kisch and related Papers, Fall 1968 (Box 1, Folder 214)
- Correspondence with Hochw. Herrn, 1960-1967 (Box 1, Folder 215)
- Correspondence with the Hebrew College Jewish Institute of Religion, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 216)
- Correspondence with Leo Adler, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 217)
- "Selbstverewigung durch Selbstheiligung" von leo Adler, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 218)
- Papers Related to W. Schwarz, "Principles and Problems of Bible Translation", 1955 (Box 1, Folder 219)
- "Heilbronn" Articleby Toni Oelsner and related Correspondence, September-November 1966 (Box 1, Folder 220)
- Correspondence with Cohen Giving Thanks for Books, June 3, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 221)
- "Germania Judaica" and related Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 222)
- Requests from Assorted Jewish Organizations, 1930-1957 (Box 1, Folder 223)
- Assorted Correspondence Concerning Procuring Books and Articles, 1938-1976 (Box 1, Folder 224)
- Correspondence with Horst Göppinger and related Papers, 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 225)
- Correspondence from Tel Aviv to a Mr. Ascher concerning Experiences in Yemen, June 21, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 226)
- "Über die gegenwärtige Staatsangehörigkeit der aus ehemals polnischen Gebieten stammenden Juden in Deutschland" by Friedrich Giese (Box 1, Folder 227)
- Papers related to Edward Strauss (Box 1, Folder 228)
- Correspondence Between Edward E. Klein and Kisch, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 229)
- Release for "The Jews of Czechoslovakia", April-June 1972 (Box 1, Folder 230)
- Correspondence Between Isaac Barzilay and Kisch, March-October 1970 (Box 1, Folder 231)
- Papers Related to "History of the Jews in South Africa", 1928-1937 (Box 1, Folder 232)
- Papers on Arthur Hertzberg's "The Zionist Idea", April 27, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 233)
- Correspondence with Institutum Judaicum Delitzschianum, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 234)
- Correspondence with Hermann Greive, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 235)
- "Der jüdische Friedhof" von Gustav Cohn and related Papers, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 236)
- Correspondence About Book Exchanges, July 8-14, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 237)
- Correspondence with Stiehm, January 20, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 238)
- Correspondence related to Events in Köln, 1931-1936 (Box 1, Folder 239)